# Henk van der Schuur Curriculum Vitæ

# **Personal Details**

H.W. van der Schuur hwschuur@gmail.com 답 linkedin.com/in/hwschuur 답 +31 6 51 26 32 40 답



## **About Me**

I bring clarity to complexity by aligning people, purpose, and technology. I strive for excellence, grounded in integrity and transparency. I believe that honest leadership and human connection are what make real progress possible.

Areas of expertise IT Strategy, Business Development, Product Management

# **Employment**

# **Schuberg Philis**

#### **Customer Director, 2017-present**

- I work with diverse expert teams for customers in vital industries, taking full end-to-end and P&L responsibility. We root out the business challenges behind the technology questions to deliver high-quality, tailored, impactful solutions that meet the highest standards of security, reliability, and performance.
- · Member of the Public, Utility, and Retail (PUR) leadership team
- · Member of the COM Council

#### **AFAS Software**

#### Platform Manager, 2015-2017

- Designed and architected the successor of the successful AFAS Profit product stack: AFAS NEXT (now AFAS SB), a fully generated, cloud-based ERP suite tailored to customer organizations through ontological models
- Founded the AMUSE research initiative: a collaboration between academic partners (Vrije Universiteit Amsterdam, Utrecht University) and industry partners (AFAS Software).

#### Product Manager, 2011-2015

- End-to-end responsible for the roadmap, design, build, and delivery of the AFAS Profit ERP software suite
- Shipped more than 150 projects across Profit Finance, CRM, Projects, Order Management, and Subscriptions to more than 10,000 customers in retail, education, healthcare, construction, wholesale and other industries

## **Utrecht University**

#### PhD Researcher, 2008-2011

- Conducted a PhD research directed at revealing the potential of software feedback, i.e., knowledge of in-the-field software operation, within Dutch independent software vendors. Created Nuntia, a binary instrumentation and recompilation tool. Successfully defended my PhD thesis after 3,5 years of research
- Led an industry workgroup with software vendors from the Netherlands, bridging academics and industry to gain early feedback and share research results

# Stabiplan (now Trimble)

Senior Software Engineer, 2008–2011

# **DEVENTIT**

Junior Software Engineer, 2003-2008

# **Education**

- · PhD in Information Science, Utrecht University, 2011
- · Master in Information Science (Business Informatics research master), Utrecht University, 2008
- · Bachelor in Computer Science (Business Studies minor), Utrecht University, 2006
- · VWO (Natuur & Techniek; Informatica, Economie 1), Griftland College, 2003

# **Selected Publications and Talks**

# **Popular**

- Adding Soul to the System: Our Strive for DevOps Significance @ DevOpsDays Amsterdam, 2024. Duo talk.
- Be More than a Product Owner—Start Product Thinking @ Medium, 2023. Story.
- Manifesto for a Product Mindset in Agile Development @ Tweakers Developers Summit, 2022. Conference talk.
- BizDevOps: Bridging the Dominant Divide between Business and IT (2) DevOpsDays Amsterdam, 2020. Keynote talk.
- Bye Bye Time & Materials—Entering the Era of Agile, Value-based Agreements (2) Agile Amsterdam, 2019. Conference talk.
- Pakketleveranciers laks—Softwaremakers kijken te weinig naar praktijksituatie bij klanten. 2 Automatisering Gids, 19, 2011. Featured cover article.

#### **Academic**

- H. van der Schuur, E. van de Ven, R. de Jong, D. Schunselaar, H.A. Reijers, M. Overeem, M. de Graaf, S. Jansen and S. Brinkkemper. **NEXT: Generating Tailored ERP Cloud Applications from Ontological Enterprise Models** In PoEM'17: Proceedings of the 10th IFIP WG 8.1. Working Conference on the Practice of Enterprise Modeling. Springer, 2017, pp. 283–298.
- H. van der Schuur. **Process Improvement through Software Operation Knowledge—If the SOK Fits, Wear It!** \( \text{\textit{Z}} \) PhD dissertation. Utrecht University, 2011.
- H. van der Schuur, S. Jansen and S. Brinkkemper. **Reducing Maintenance Effort through Software Operation Knowledge: An Eclectic Empirical Evaluation** 1. In CSMR'11: Proceedings of the 15th European Conference on Software Maintenance and Reengineering. IEEE Computer Society, 2011, pages 201–210.

## **Selected Guest Lectures**

- · Advanced Program Zorgmanagement: Strategie & Digitale Transformatie. Nyenrode Business Universiteit, 2023–2024.
- · Innovation in Practice: Data & Al. Nyenrode Business Universiteit, 2023–2024.
- · Software Production and Software Product Management. Utrecht University, 2014–2019.

# **Licenses and Certifications**

- · Nyenrode Masterclass Bedrijfskunde voor niet-bedrijfskundigen
- · Tuff Leadership Training (Step 1, Step 2)
- · AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner; Microsoft Certified Azure Fundamentals AZ-900
- Passenger car (B); heavy motorcycle (AZ); passenger car with trailer (BE)
- · PADI Advanced Open Water Diver